How do you reform them? How do you
reform CIA?
>> You're going to have to tear the place
down to the studs and you're going to
have to enact real controls. You're
spying on members of Congress. What do
you mean there's nothing to see here
move along?
>> Maybe because as governments degrade all
of the power vests in the executive and
the people who think they're just like
hegeimons from birth and the affluence
will never end. It
>> doesn't work out.
>> No.
Tucker Carlson and John Kiryaku just sat
down to discuss the evils of the CIA
saying it must be abolished with Kiryaku
saying it must be torn up by the studs.
They get into the evils that the CIA has
done, how they think controls can be
used against it and what's at stake if
we don't dismantle the intelligence
apparatus that propagandizes Americans
into war and wages psychological warfare
on the American people. So, let's get
right into it. Please like the video and
subscribe to the channel.
>> How do you reform them? How do you
reform CIA?
>> You're going to have to tear the place
down to the studs. And you're going to
have to enact real controls.
I'll give you an example, and this may
sound silly, but I think it's important.
When I first joined the CIA, I had
literally no idea the political views of
the people that I was that I was working
with. no idea,
I should say, with whom I was working.
Um, in 1996,
a woman that I sat next to got in
trouble for discreetly taping up a Bob
Dole for president bumper sticker in her
own cubicle. She was called to HR. She
was reprimanded, had a memo put in her
file. she wasn't eligible for promotion
for a year because she had violated the
the cardinal rule that we do not take
political positions. And I remember
thinking, wow. And then we got to the
point in the not, you know, too distant
future where the CIA is so politicized
that you end up with 51 senior
intelligence service officers
lying in writing that the Hunter Biden
laptop bore all the hallmarks of a
Russian intelligence operation,
information operation. Like h how did we
get there? I had no idea. I'll give you
another example. The the 1992 election,
we had a morning meeting like we did
every morning. Every group in the in the
entire CIA has its morning meeting at
9:00 to just discuss whatever happened
in the region that you cover the night
before. And my boss said at that end of
that morning meeting, he said, "I know
we're not supposed to do this, but I'm
just really curious who you guys voted
for this morning." And I thought, "Oh,
yeah. We never talk about stuff like
that." I still remember it was three for
Bush, three for Clinton, and two for
Perau. And I remember thinking, "Wow,
that's interesting." But I would never
have known. Well, now it's like, you
know, everybody was in bed with Obama.
Everybody was in bed with Biden. How did
that happen? Well, the CIA has become a
political instrument. And to say that
it's not supposed to be a political
instrument is laughable. Kiryaku is
exposing that here. And ultimately, not
only is it a political instrument, it
happens to be a political instrument
driven by Israel and driven by the
lobbies, the military industrial complex
that benefits from the wars. They
propagandize Americans into the banks
for profiting off of them, big oil and
big energy much of the time. As with
Venezuela, doesn't seem like we're
really getting the proceeds from that.
The first barrels from Venezuela under
this arrangement shipped to Israel, of
course. But yeah, the CIA is a
demonstrally evil political machine.
That's exactly what it does. It wages
psychological warfare, thought control,
mind control experiments on the public
through MK Ultra and Operation
Mockingbird. And again, propagandizes
and lays the groundwork for Americans to
accept all these foreign wars that have
destroyed our country at the peril of
Americans for some perceived benefit of
the Ludnik, Netanyahu, and the Greater
Israel Project. How did we get there so
quickly when you know what the rules
are? The rules are very clear. No
politics. It's all about keeping the
country safe until it's not until it's
about politics.
And so I think that to reform the place,
you have to tear it down and then
rebuild. And you have to have real rules
that are really followed that you just
cannot be political. you can't and then
you know maybe even this probably would
be unconstitutional but maybe you put
the brakes on political involvement for
12 months or 18 months after you leave
just like there are brakes on lobbying.
You can't just go from Friday afternoon
you leave your job and Monday morning
you begin as a lobbyist lobbying your
former colleagues. You can't do that.
>> Well, one way would be to make it more
political. So CIA has the fewest
political appointees of any agency.
That's right. I think there are three or
four something like that.
>> That's it.
>> There's like no civilian control at this
point. Supposed to be the intel
agencies, but there I mean the intel
committees
>> in the House and Senate, but that
>> cheerleaders.
>> Yeah, of course.
The weakest, drunkest, most compromised
people to sit on those committees.
The conferences do not vote on me on the
membership or the chairman or or vice
chairman of the intelligence committees.
The intelligence committees are select
committees. They're not standing
committees. And so it's leadership that
appoints all of the members.
>> Yeah. It's a deep state bureaucracy.
It's an evil machine and it is a
political instrument wielded more often
against the American people. We're
supposed to believe that the CIA
protects us. They go Americans into
supporting these wars, wage
psychological warfare against the
American people, and they have torture
programs pretending that that keeps
Americans safe, where that drives
atrocities against US service members
abroad. It's a horrifying institution.
It needs to be scrapped. I'm with
Kuryaku 100%. I would even go further
than Kiryaku when he said, "Yeah, you
have to rip it down completely." And
then he said, "And rebuild." I say,
"Don't rebuild." I say no rebuilding
effort whatsoever. The country sustained
itself in a more tranquil position in
terms of foreign policy for what
something like 150 years more than that
without CIA. That's what we need. So if
you accept that this institution is
evil, that it's counterintuitive, that
it actually hurts the interests of the
American people, then you would accept
that there's no way to essentially
reform it. That doesn't mean that I
wouldn't accept one day, if it were
possible, the cutting of the budget,
which is, by the way, a shadow budget.
They don't tell the public about what
the CIA's true budget is, nefariously
so. But if you could get that budget to
be shaved in half, I would accept that.
But the Northstar should always be
abolishing the CIA. It's an evil
instrument. And saying it can be
reformed if we, you know, elect the
right people to it, switch the policies
here and there, it's like saying, well,
you know, slaveryy's evil. we should
just reform it to be more palatable. You
know, 10% less whipping or appoint
different overseers on the plantation.
Well, no. That's an injustice regardless
of what it does. I'd accept curtailments
of any violations of liberty completely,
but it has to be destroyed. That's
always the northstar of the dissident. I
won't accept anything else. Now, let's
take a moment to thank our sponsor, The
Wellness Company, because studies on
social media are drawing attention to
the rise of colorctyl cancer among young
adults. Since 2005, colurectal cancer
deaths have increased in people under
50. And just for the record, chat GPT
confirms that 65% of private oncologists
revenue comes from prescribing
chemotherapy. Could recent turbo cancer
in the young be just a coincidence?
Well, the news is plenty of studies now
show that traditional treatments are no
longer the only choice. For example,
Anthony Latai, director of the National
Cancer Institute, recently acknowledged
scientific interest in more rigorous
preclinical studies of ivormectin's
effects on cancer cells. The wellness
company is a pioneer of medical freedom.
Their medical board has stayed on the
pulse of offlabel cancer solutions
success stories and studies removing red
tape for you to easily access
alternative medicines. Introducing
Americanmade Ivormectin, safe, trusted,
tested, and produced locally in Florida.
Ivormectin has been prescribed globally
for more than 30 years and even earned
the Nobel Prize in medicine for its
proven ability to eliminate parasites.
The wellness company is offering an 18
mgram dose for just 350 per tablet.
You'll get a 6-month supply of 84
tablets at an unbeatable price. Get your
US-made ivormectin and your own health.
twwc.health/vault.
You'll get $30 off plus free shipping.
Now, let's get back into the
conversation.
>> The fix is in from the beginning.
>> Of course. No, the whole thing is
absurd. And I have to say as I go down
the roster, you know, of the members of
those committees, I'm like, "Oh, that
per they're the most screwed up people
in the entire Congress." It's true.
>> Yeah. Oh, I'm aware. Oh, I know them.
So, um, why wouldn't you return some
measure of public control to CIA?
>> You know, I hadn't thought of it that
way, but that's actually a good idea. If
you have
if you have a senior intelligence
service that's embedded, it's not going
anywhere. They're there for 30 35 years,
right?
>> And they're going to be anti- anti-
president or anti-Republican,
>> then maybe you do need political
appointees to keep the honest people.
>> Well, the public ought to have some
control over what its government is
doing, right?
>> Yeah, you can say that again.
>> Yeah. I spoke with a I spoke with a
senator a couple of days ago. I don't
want to betray a confidence, so I'm
going to be careful with my language.
Um, he
has entered into something of a dispute
with the intelligence committee and they
just won't budge. And what he's asking
for is legitimately under his purview as
the chairman of another committee having
to do with security, foreign policy, you
know, intelligence, whatever. And the
CIA won't budge, the intelligence
committee won't budge. And he said, I I
don't know what to do. And I said, well,
you've got to approach leadership. He
said, that was the first place I went.
And leadership said, they don't want to
get involved in a dispute between two
chairmen.
So what do you do when everybody on the
intelligence committee is there just to
serve the CIA, not to oversee it? That
exposes what these committees are.
They're spokesman for a deep state
apparatus that they don't really have
palpable control over. Just think of
that. Most of our senators are already
one over to national lobbies to big
tech, big oil, the military-industrial
complex, the Israel lobby, big pharma,
big medical, etc. And even that makes
them just beyond the scope of American
influence for the most part. The few
select exceptions. I would say Ran Paul
is the closest to this and really the
best man we have there right now. And I
don't know that he's referring to Rand
Paul. I I I would assume he's not just
out of, you know, percentagebased, you
know, realities or consequences here.
But they don't have control over the
deep state apparatus. They don't have
control over the CIA. The CIA is
effectively a shadow government, and it
has been since its inception. It was
involved in coups against the will of
the American electorate, not only in
Iran in 1953. That one's pretty ironic
given recent circumstances. Guatemala in
54, an attempted overthrow of the Castro
government in the Bay of Pigs, and then
planning a false flag operation,
Operation Northwoods, that would have
killed Americans to try to support this
effort. It's been evil from the start.
Arthur Slesinger wrote an email to
Kennedy warning of this and saying like
it just needs to be dismantled. They're
running shadow operations in
contradiction to the will of the
American electorate and even the
president. It's been that way from the
start. Not to ensure that it follows the
law, just to cheerlead for it.
>> They spied on members of Congress and
were never punished for it.
>> Never. I remember Eric Holder saying,
"Now, now
I got these referrals, these criminal
referrals. Everybody needs to calm down.
Nobody's going to be investigated. What
do you mean nobody's going to be
investigated? The CIA broke into the
computer system of the Senate
Intelligence Committee to steal the
information that was being developed
there about the torture program. You're
spying on members of Congress. What do
you mean there's nothing to see here?
Move along. It was a crime, but never
prosecuted.
Do you have any hope that the government
will return to its original purpose
which is serving the population of the
country?
>> I've consistently been criticized as
being too optimistic in life about
everything. I'm always a glass half
full.
>> It's a great way to be.
>> I I'm I'm I'm
happy with the way I lead my life
>> on this. I I can't see any reason at all
to be optimistic.
>> Really? Yeah.
>> Yeah. There are no more Frank Churches
or Barry Goldwaters or, you know, real
leaders, real leaders. I mean, even Tip
O'Neal recognized that Congress was a
co-equal participant in government and
which drove Jimmy Carter nuts,
>> but but allowed him to negotiate
successfully with Ronald Reagan.
Why can't we have that? That worked.
>> Yeah, I wouldn't say that worked. That
was during a time where the CIA was
still entrenching its tentacles into
policy again against the will of the
American electorate, against the will of
the government. But I generally agree
that there's not real promise for this
to be changed from the inside. I would,
you know, push back a little bit on
Kiryaku. I do think we have that in very
small numbers. I think we have that in
Thomas Massie especially. So Ran Paul to
a lesser extent sometimes when she was
in there, Marjorie Taylor Green um on on
some issues. I would even say Ron Widen
has been good on issues of transparency,
but overwhelmingly he is right. I don't
see a sense that there's a real
political movement from within
Washington that's ready to go against
this beast that is the intelligence
apparatus. That's why I think you need
to use nullification local policies to
push back against the egregious and
immoral and unconstitutional violations
of the feds. It becomes hard when part
of it is just the, you know, the the war
apparatus under the intelligence
services, but the the states need to
deprive US agencies of water and and
resources and local law enforcement
assistance and even electricity if
that's what it takes to starve out this
evil beast known as the CIA. And that
goes for the NSA, the FBI, etc. All of
these criminal organizations don't need
to exist. Americans would go fine into
the future without them more so than we
are now because they draw us into these
endless wars, these endless conflicts
and propagandizes us in that direction.
Why can't we go back to that?
>> I don't know.
>> Maybe because as governments degrade all
of the power vests in the executive.
>> I think that's what
>> and the framers understood that.
>> And then you I'm going to come back to
Lindsey Graham just because I have so
little respect for him. Then you have
Lindsey Graham saying, "We need a weaker
Congress." I mean, that's essentially
what he's saying about the War Powers
Act.
>> Well, he's a totalitarian, so of course
he wants that.
>> How does Lindsey Like, what is that
exactly? Why do the intel agencies and
the government of Israel seem to have so
much control over Lindsey Graham?
>> I don't know. Ted Cruz is the same way.
>> Yeah. What is that? And it's both people
with weird personal lives.
>> Yes.
>> Is that connected?
>> Wow. You're going to get me started now.
Uh, I think
>> well I just notice it. I notice it.
Every everybody I know who's a
cheerleader for the worst things is
vulnerable in some way.
>> I think there's probably something to
that.
>> Mhm. You know, it's funny.
>> Probably something to that.
>> Alan Dersowitz once said that the most
intelligent student he ever had was Ted
Cruz.
>> I I don't get that. I mean, I I want my
elected officials to be smarter than I
am. I want them to think outside.
>> Yeah, me too. And I don't get that
either. Frankly, you had Ted Cruz in
that conversation with Tucker Carlson
skewering Tucker for supposedly being so
obsessed with Israel like 3 minutes
removed from saying, "I made it my top
prerogative when becoming a senator to
be the most pro-Israel senator in the
government." Just think about that.
That's the most intelligent guy. That's
the guy that's trying to sell you on his
role as a senator within the government
is he calls Tucker obsessed with Israel
when he backs Israel to the hilt. He's
totally Israel first. That's why he was
a never Trumper back in 2016 cuz Trump
actually had relatively good rhetoric
for a time on the campaign trail till he
was won over completely by the Israel
lobby saying, "Hey, we needed to be
neutral in the conflict between the
Palestinians and the Israelis." He and
Levvin and Lindsey Graham and Ben
Shapiro and all these Israel first
lunatics became never Trumpers because
they feared we would move away from
these constant forever wars spurred on
largely because of the CIA and the
propaganda apparatus. Well, they've lost
control of the propaganda apparatus. I'm
glad to say with the rise of independent
media, you know, social media driving
news much more than those idiots in
Washington that exist to serve the
lobbies and a foreign country. But I
don't know if there's really any linkage
behind their personalities or not. What
I can say is they're complete slaps in
the face to Americans that care about
our sovereignty, catering to our
interests, America first for once, which
is just a completely abandoned construct
under this administration and all other
administrations that said they'd serve
the public. No, they serve the national
lobbies, the intelligence services, and
Israel and Ukraine. That's what they do.
>> He thought Ted Cruz was a genius. Yeah,
that's what he said.
>> I can say as someone who knows Ted
really, really well, that's not a word
that's ever come to mind. Blib
>> Mhm.
>> But you know, blibness is not IQ.
>> Yeah.
>> Not a wise man at all. Not a
well-informed man at all.
>> That's what I mean. there there are no
Birch buys or or I mean on both sides
Birch B uh Frank Church Bob Dole Barry
Goldwater Ted Kennedy these these
thinkers that gave us the government
that we had in the 60s the 70s the 80s
they're just gone
>> right
yeah all victims of affluence and
>> just flaccid thinking which was a result
of flaccid living
>> you It was nice to worry about nuclear
annihilation every day because it makes
you sharper. We were talking off camera
about the the governments around the
world that we respect have dealt with
think are impressive and smart and
they're all countries that can't take
anything for granted.
>> That's right.
>> That are constantly fighting for their
own survival, having to calculate
>> everything from eight different angles.
Like those are the most impressive
people and the people who think they're
just like hegeimons from birth and the
affluence will never end. It
>> doesn't work out.
>> No. Mm-m.
Well, I partially agree with what
they're saying. We don't have true
statesmen, but my definition of true
statesmen is a little bit more rigid
than I think Kiryakuz is. Ted Kennedy, I
mean, the guy murdered Mary Joe Capeti.
And it's it's insane to think that he
was, you know, this wise, you know,
political figure. He was a total
maniacal killer that didn't have to pay
for his his murder of the woman in
Chapaquitic. The movie for that's
interesting. I haven't studied that
issue so closely, but the guy was
clearly a murderer. He was a deep state
chill supporting the wars, supporting
endless corporate welfare, individual
welfare, the regulatory state, etc. Bir,
I might give him that. Bob Dole. I again
this is an establishment figure that was
well connected to the intelligence
services. I don't consider those guys
great statesmen. If we're talking great
statesmen, we have to talk about John
Taylor of Caroline or James Randolph of
Rowenoke or John C. Calhoun. Even
statesmen that I didn't like like Daniel
Webster or Henry Clay were more
pronounced in their intelligence and
their influence and you know the early
antibbellum era than anything that's
come out in the last century. That's for
sure. But when it comes down to it, I
think these two are generally right. You
can't really reform the CIA. It's too
evil. And again, like I said earlier,
calling for the CIA to be reformed,
saying, you know, if we just mix up the
sauce a little bit, change the policy,
appoint different people, maybe
restructure a bit, that will be to the
liking of Americans. It's like saying we
can reform cattle slavery. different
plantations, different overseers, lesser
amounts of whipping, maybe more
privileges here or there for the slaves,
maybe teach them to read and write. I'm
sorry, that just doesn't cut it. That's
still evil. If you reform evil, you're
still left with some percentage of evil.
And my north star will always be to
abolishing the evil, abolishing the
warfare state and the intelligence
services that encourage it, especially
the CIA, the FBI, the NSA. NSA
collecting data on all Americans with
Palunteer expanding that surveillance
state now without warrants shredding the
fourth amendment and really doing the
bidding of foreign countries and
national lobbies above the American
people. You know, Donald Trump rode into
the White House originally on a famous
speech where he said, "Americanism, not
globalism, will be our credo." But what
he's really done is saying deep state
corruption and Zionism will be our
credo, not Americanism. So we've traded
globalism for deep statism and uh
Zionism. That's what we get when we back
the intelligence services. They must be
eliminated. There's no other way. You
can't reform them. You certainly can't
reform them by putting in Cash Patel to
cover up the Epstein scandal. You know,
close the door on foreign angles into
the Charlie Kirk assassination.
you know, and just be fine with it. You
know, I miss the days when Cash Patel's
rhetoric was, "We need to close down the
FBI Hoover building and make it into a
museum to the deep state." Well, I think
we're going to be waiting a long time
until the FBI Hoover building is closed.
But that's where we sit. The CIA must be
abolished. No ifands or buts about it.
I've seen Tucker say that on Pierce
Morgan and on other shows. And John
Kiyaku makes that plain here. So, what
do you guys think? Does the CIA need to
be abolished? Is there any chance it can
be reformed at all? Let me know in the
comments down below. Like the video,
subscribe to the channel. Also,
subscribe to Tucker. Really like this
segment. Great guest. Kuryaku is always
interesting and he has a lot of
background and is an American hero for
whistleblowing on the CIA torture
program. And if you like this video,
please consider joining as a YouTube
member of Liberty Vault. You can do that
by clicking the join button down below.
And doing that gets you immediate access
to all my videos before they go live to
the general public on YouTube. members
get to view those membersonly videos
right away and I appreciate their
support. Also, if you want a free copy
of my first book, Compact of the
Republic, click the link in the
description down below. That'll send you
off to a website. You just plug in your
email right there and I'll send you a
full free copy of that book. No
obligation whatsoever. And look, I have
a few demands from the sinister Israel
first corrupt deep state intelligence
operative regime, and I won't apologize
for it. No more war, no more debt, no
more inflation, and no more empire.
Peace out, guys. Catch you in the next
one.